### Contact

urvi032@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/urvisharma18 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Artificial Intelligence (AI)
Unsupervised Learning
Continuous Integration and
Continuous Delivery (CI/CD)

#### Certifications

Tableau Desktop Certified Professional Certification Experiential Network R Statistics Essential Training SQL Essential Training

# Urvashi Sharma

Data Analyst| Predictive Analytics | Machine Learning | Artificial Intelligence | Data Strategy

Boston, Massachusetts, United States

## Summary

Urvashi is a motivated data professional with 6 yrs of experience and recently graduated with master's degree in Data Analytics from Northeastern University, Boston. She is a seasoned data nerd with a can-do attitude who doesn't just go for quick results but truly unlocks data potential and provides elegant solutions. Urvashi is a self-starter and a true team player. She always looks for creative ways to make things more efficient and add business value by solving complex data problems.

Urvashi has extensive experience in data analysis, data modeling & warehousing, statistical modeling, data visualizations/dashboards, predictive algorithms, machine learning, data integration using REST API's and expert-level programming skills in SQL, Python, R, Tableau, Data warehousing, Google Cloud Platform.

## Experience

Tata Consultancy Services
Lead System/ Data Engineer
December 2016 - Present (6 years 5 months)
United States

Lead dashboard development/Analytics initiatives – including data prep by extracting data from different databases like AWS, SQL Server, Oracle ODS and Mongo DB and used Python to build out predictive models and used Tableau for developing presentation layer in customer facing dashboards. Developed POCs in Artificial Intelligence to train the data in unsupervised learning.

Identifying tasks that could be improved through automation and performing low to medium complexity source code development.

Investigating, diagnosing, and correcting system issues, developing new programs and coding individual programs.

Gathering & analyzing requirements, interacting with other teams daily.

Build CI/CD pipelines for different kind of requirements, prepared blueprints for different application types and User documentation and training on Build Master tool.

Samsara
Data Analytics Engineer Co-Op
January 2022 - July 2022 (7 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

Northeastern University Student Success Guide August 2021 - May 2022 (10 months) Boston, Massachusetts, United States

Undergrad student onboarding and check in and provide them support for mentorship, Tutoring, academic advisors, job search.

We truly understand student needs and recommend them the right resources.

### Education

Northeastern University

Master's degree, MPS Analytics · (January 2021 - December 2022)

YMCA University of Science & Technology

Master of Technology - MTech, Computer Engineering · (2014 - 2016)

YMCA University of Science & Technology

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Computer Engineering · (2009 - 2013)